<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.0.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-03-26T13:01:40-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Lawrence Wang</title><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title type="html">Corona, College, and Us</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/corona" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Corona, College, and Us" /><published>2020-03-20T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2020-03-20T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/corona</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/corona">&lt;p&gt;The problematic thing about an international public health emergency that forces the closure of schools, restaurants, and social events, aside from the fact that I’ve been rotting away at home and can’t even find solace in the slim chance that I might be able to go to Glastonbury over the summer since both Glastonbury and London and my study abroad program are likely cancelled, is the fact that I can’t even listen to music in peace anymore. I’ve always found it interesting, the way we are conditioned to associate certain memories with music and how they evoke the same emotional and conscious response every time, but never have I found it so infuriating. So many song in my Spotify library have such distinct moments written across them that it becomes impossible to listen to practically anything without wondering, with the utmost confusion, where did my freshman year go?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;cruel-summer&quot;&gt;Cruel Summer&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Lover&lt;/em&gt; dropped while I was digging holes to defecate in and hating my life in the Appalachian wilderness, so I did not get to hear the album first hand. But I did the moment I got my lovely T-Mobile 4G LTE network back, and on the bus from New Hampshire to Connecticut I heard it and fell asleep. The standout from the album, and what absolutely should have been the lead single, was Cruel Summer, a song that combines everything I loved in the New Romantics - Getaway Car trajectory.  Now, it reminds me of Camp Yale So. Damn. Much. When I listen to it I can hear my own yearning in those early college days, the hope for some exquisite chance encounter to befall upon me, the days in New Haven when it was warm enough for shorts — I can feel the breeze blowing by my legs. It makes me think of lying in the Silliman courtyard, walking down Wall Street for another info session, going to Starbucks to get a venti water and keeping the cup for the whole month because it had a straw, sitting in the common room of people whose world views you weren’t sure aligned with yours and yet, at that moment, you were just happy to be there. Cruel Summer is inclusion and strangeness, excitement and fear, hope and the aftermath when bubbles of hope are popped one by one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;california&quot;&gt;California&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Though written about wanting someone back, California is when sadness seeps through the semi-permeable membrane you’ve built to guard yourself. “You’re scared to win, scared to lose. I’ve heard the war was over if you really choose” reminds me of the light drizzles that occupied New Haven’s winter, and walking down Hillhouse in midst of the rain without an umbrella. The moments when nostalgia rushes to my head and says: California, In-N-Out, Sprouts, Brown Cow, Sharetea, they melted with academic burdens that seem like nothing in retrospect, but were suffocating at the time, in Lana’s slow murmuring.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;beautiful-ghosts&quot;&gt;Beautiful Ghosts&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had been anticipating this release for more than a month, ever since hearing the 10 second clip in Cats promotion — a movie I was actually hoping to see but never did because I got scared after reading the reviews. Well, at least the song turned out to be great and made me cry that Friday at 1 A.M. In the coming weeks I blasted the song in the common room so many times that all my suite mates grew tired of it. Today it still gives me chills, especially the “I never knew I’d love this world they’ve let me into” moment, which makes me think of all the internship rejections I received, in addition to wondering about spending the summer in London, which is no longer happening so idk who I was kidding.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;light-on&quot;&gt;Light On&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I first discovered &lt;em&gt;Heard It In A Past Life&lt;/em&gt; I thought I found a gem: Maggie Rogers’s debut was sensational and genuine. Now when I listen to it I see New York. I see the time we ate hot pot and got Boba Guys on the TD sponsored trip, and how we had to scuffle our way through the Times Square crowd to catch the bus. I see the Old Navy in Midtown, the Ding Tea, and the Shake Shack in Grand Central. I think of that one night in New York, when I was planning on staying at NYU until I learned about their stupid policy regarding overnight guests, at which point I decided I would take a 1-hour subway ride uptown at 1 A.M. and completely embarrass myself by entering my friend’s apartment complex, looking assured about where I’m headed because I did not want to interact with the lobby staff, and walking into a random elevator that, as it turns out, did not go to his floor. There was also no signal in the building, so I had to wander around the third floor for 30 minutes before I found another elevator. I woke up the next morning at 7, and sat down at a nearby Starbucks thinking: “Wow, this must be what college is like.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another time, after briefly stopping by the NYU Weinstein lounge where Chinese international students were playing mafia until 3 A.M., I walked to the 8th Street Station to get to JFK for my 8 A.M. flight. There was not a single soul in the station, so instead of waiting on the empty, eerie platform for the N train which never came, I dragged my suitcases up the stairs into the rain. It was cold. I was alone. My bags were drenched. But I enjoyed having the streets to myself — it felt regal, and I liked how the lights were blurred by downpour, then reflected by puddles, then shattered by droplets hitting the surface. &lt;strong&gt;Light On reminds me of the rain that night.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;if-the-world-was-ending&quot;&gt;If the World Was Ending&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I love the first line of the song “I was distracted and in traffic, I didn’t feel it when the earthquake happened” because I don’t feel earthquakes when I’m in cars, except for that one time when I did, after which I drove to Urban Outfitters and got boba. The song makes me think of staying at friends’ suite until late, watching them dance to Super Bass, eating McDonald’s and getting stomach cramps afterwards. Now, although my freshman year is in shambles, school is shut down, borders are closed, I still don’t want to forget anything that happened because it was one of those remarkable moments in time when everything felt exciting; and here’s a customary Taylor Swift quote: “We’re all really sad that this is ending, but we’re really happy because of what it was.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the death toll becoming more and more “just a number,” the hysterical shopping for toilet paper, the staying at home and not getting Chick-fil-A or tofu for months to come, I reckon it feels pretty much like the end of the world. But trust, though I might not be able to get out of my house arrest to stay the night, that it will be fine — corona is not down for forever anyway.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Personal" /><category term="Reflection" /><category term="Featured" /><summary type="html">The problematic thing about an international public health emergency that forces the closure of schools, restaurants, and social events, aside from the fact that I’ve been rotting away at home and can’t even find solace in the slim chance that I might be able to go to Glastonbury over the summer since both Glastonbury and London and my study abroad program are likely cancelled, is the fact that I can’t even listen to music in peace anymore. I’ve always found it interesting, the way we are conditioned to associate certain memories with music and how they evoke the same emotional and conscious response every time, but never have I found it so infuriating. So many song in my Spotify library have such distinct moments written across them that it becomes impossible to listen to practically anything without wondering, with the utmost confusion, where did my freshman year go?</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Suburbia</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/suburbia" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Suburbia" /><published>2020-01-23T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2020-01-23T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/suburbia</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/suburbia">&lt;p&gt;When it comes to goodbyes, I’m experienced, or so I thought. Last summer, I said goodbye to skipping school for a Starbucks run under the 90-degree California sun. Before that, I said goodbye to lunch under woven canopies that never stopped the rain from wetting our food. Further back, I said goodbye to the comforts of motherland and native tongue. Moving across the country for college? It’ll be a piece of cake, I told myself as I hugged my brother and bid farewell to my parents. Before I knew it, I was out the door.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Arriving was disorienting to say the least: the chaos, the welcomes, the dragging-suitcases-across-campus, the unfamiliar faces. Everything was new and strange. The Vineyard Vines, the way people say “bubble tea” instead of “boba,” the fact that Shake Shack, instead of McDonald’s, takes center stage in the town, the sheer number of people from &lt;em&gt;New Jersey&lt;/em&gt;. New, for sure. But exciting also, right?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the time, I agreed. New is good, different is good, and sentimentality is overrated, I thought. But as I lay in a tarp tent on the First-Year Outdoor Orientation Trip, I was overcome by a sudden longing. Newness became fear, and fear graduated into longing for home. I started to miss a lot of things. The nights when Dad sat in front of his computer, crossing off items on a list: ropes for climbing, boots for hiking, sprays for bug bites, down jacket for winter, bedding that must be Egyptian cotton with 800 thread count. Some of them from Amazon, some of them brought all the way across the ocean in family friends’ suitcases. The warm smell of the tofu fried pork belly embellished with vibrant green pepper, and Mom knew just the amount of spice to add without having me chug down potsful of water. The way Dad walked by my desk at exactly midnight with a palmful of vitamins before he went to bed because he knew I always forget them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During my last couple days at home, Dad kept repeating how “by the time you leave for college, you will have already spent 93% of the time you will ever spend with us.” I didn’t pay much mind to it then, I thought it’s a moment worth celebrating, a new page. I wanted to commemorate it, not to let the end dim the sparkle of the story. But when I was enthralled by the new, what I always seem to forget is how much I rely on the old.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the first night of elementary school when all the kids were scrambling out of the dorm and screaming playing jump rope on the moonlit field, I pulled the teacher aside and pointed to the apartment building barely visible behind layers of leaves and said “look, that’s my home.” Weren’t my eyes teary then? On one of the first nights in the U.S., after coming back from Denny’s and trash-talking American food, I sat on the balcony of our new house and sighed “this doesn’t feel like home” and how Mom looked up at the blank ceiling, her smile forced and bitter. It didn’t feel like home to her either.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We always took on the shifts and goodbyes in life together, me and my family. In elementary school, nights in the dorm were lonely, but every weekend, I went home. Then we would drive across the city to East Lake, where there’d be cherry blossoms by the pagoda in the spring and water lilies roaming the surface in the summer. When we first moved to L.A., we endured the miscommunications with the water meter together, the unwilling-to-engage with The Home Depot employees together, the too-afraid-to-order at restaurants together. And until that common denominator was ripped away from me, I never quite grasped the value of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the final get-together with my high school friends, we watched &lt;em&gt;The Farewell&lt;/em&gt;. My favorite scene was the ending, when Awkwafina stops in the middle of the busy New York street and shouts at the top of her lungs. The sound ripples all the way back to her hometown in China, scaring a flock of birds out of the tree by her grandma’s house. It makes me wonder sometimes, when I scream in the shower hoping none of my floormates notice, would my family hear me? Is Mom tending to her succulents? Is Dad compulsively wringing the clothes out of the washing machine for the fifth time? Are they alright?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But isn’t that the beauty of growing up? You become more and more alone until you’re all that’s left on the road. When I was young, I thought I could be anything, Premier of the State Council, CEO of a Fortune 500, scientist discovering the next big thing, until I realized I could be none of those. Because at the time, I didn’t know I would volunteer at two research labs and end up abhorring both, I didn’t know my dad was detained by the Communist Party for two months under false allegations, I didn’t know I missed the recruitment mark for my elementary school by two points and wouldn’t have been able to attend if not for the 5,000 yuan my mom gave to her friend with a connection.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It sounds like a grim world, but I’d say growing up is not necessarily the process of discovering a darker world. At seven-years-old, everything was shiny and splendid. Now I realize it seemed magical and wonderful because back then, everything was simple. The people who love me shielded me from the complex, the blurry, the despicable. The world is neither intensely beautiful nor extremely horrible. It’s just difficult and complicated, and neither the good nor the bad present the whole truth. I’ve learned that growing up is accepting the complicated world, accepting the gap between reality and expectation, and still choosing to believe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I guess you always start off wide-eyed about everything. But the novelty wears off as soon as you come to the realization that any stranger you lay your eyes on the street might have a totally unique story, a story that might remain a mystery to you forever. You realize the planet is filled to its brink with extraordinary people doing all sorts of things. That’s why you would, while traversing the vast and lonely world, reminisce more furiously about the &lt;em&gt;suburbia&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nostalgia really is a funny thing. Most days, you don’t pay much mind to it. But at unexpected times, under unexpected circumstances, it would revolt, charge, attack with power beyond description, and leave you with insurmountable strength. Then it fades and hibernates for its next spring. Nowadays when I go home, I get reprimanded less for waking up too late or staying out too late or eating too much In-N-Out. It’s good. Different and good. I also get phone calls from home. I dread them sometimes because I know Mom would be pressing me to join Club Swimming, or badminton, or go to calligraphy class, things that I inherently hate or refuse to find the time to do. But it’s ok, it’s all love, I tell myself. It’s all love.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Personal" /><category term="Reflection" /><category term="Featured" /><summary type="html">When it comes to goodbyes, I’m experienced, or so I thought. Last summer, I said goodbye to skipping school for a Starbucks run under the 90-degree California sun. Before that, I said goodbye to lunch under woven canopies that never stopped the rain from wetting our food. Further back, I said goodbye to the comforts of motherland and native tongue. Moving across the country for college? It’ll be a piece of cake, I told myself as I hugged my brother and bid farewell to my parents. Before I knew it, I was out the door.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Lover: The Evolution of Taylor Swift</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/lover" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Lover&amp;#58; The Evolution of Taylor Swift" /><published>2019-10-20T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2019-10-20T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/lover</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/lover">&lt;p&gt;We all remember the vengeful spirit of Taylor Swift. From claiming that “there’s nothing I do better than revenge” to “bandaids don’t fix bullet holes,” a certain part of her discography was dedicated to feuds and lost loves. Just two years ago, Taylor can be seen burning bridges and throwing shades, (in addition to being &lt;em&gt;presumably dead&lt;/em&gt;) in the music video for “Look What You Made Me Do.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If &lt;em&gt;reputation&lt;/em&gt; were a product of the venom and frustration that consumed her in the aftermaths of the Kim-Kanye controversy, then &lt;em&gt;Lover&lt;/em&gt; is the complete antithesis of that. With her newest release, Taylor delivers her most stylistically diverse and artistically complete body of work yet, featuring poignant introspection, playful maturity, and most importantly, a grand forgiveness, for both her enemies and herself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Regardless of the outcome of the drama, the existence of this album is proof of Taylor taking confident strides away from the days of bitter blame games. Realizing that contentions only feed into the bloodthirsty, clickbaity headline culture of today, Taylor also concludes that there are more important issues in life, such as the health of family members (“Soon You’ll Get Better”), political advocacy (“The Man”), and finding the one true love (“Lover”).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;a-past-in-the-past&quot;&gt;A Past in the Past&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 2006, Taylor Swift debuted as a country princess. She was heralded as “America’s Sweetheart,” that curly-haired girl next door who sang about love stories and fairytales. To be fair, it was fine for the 17-years-old Taylor to be petty, to sing about failed relationships and shitty boyfriends. But it did become problematic when people, including herself, seemed to forget that sweethearts grow up too, just like prom queens do not stay young forever and memories someday fade. When she gradually became complacent with an immaturity that resorted to triviality and revenge, it felt like a stagnancy in her creative direction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The halos also meant heightened expectation from fans and critics alike. During the release for &lt;em&gt;1989&lt;/em&gt;, both Swift and her music were recognized as perfection in the Pop universe. She had the flawless image, soaring sales numbers, all-star team of friends, and an award-winning album. Yet while she has reaped the benefits of media exposure, she also suffered — because public perception is an odd thing - the same people that crowned you can turn against you just as quickly. In today’s &lt;em&gt;stan-or-cancelled&lt;/em&gt; culture, the perfection demanded by the public can be exhausting. According to a recent &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.rollingstone.com/music/music-features/taylor-swift-rolling-stone-interview-880794/&quot;&gt;interview&lt;/a&gt; with The Rolling Stone, Taylor stated that “[people] decided in 2016 that absolutely everything about me was wrong. If I did something good, it was for the wrong reasons. If I did something brave, I didn’t do it correctly. If I stood up for myself, I was throwing a tantrum. And so I found myself in this endless mockery echo chamber.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/law-wang/moodblog/master/assets/images/lover2.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Cover&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;a-new-beginning&quot;&gt;A New Beginning&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In some bizarre way, however, her fall from grace also prompted the evolution of her artistry. Her once-teenager audience are now adults, and it seemed appropriate for her to grow out of the expectations and halos that once chained her. She did lose her perfect image, but in the death of her reputation, she became aware of the delicacy of herself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The Archer” is Taylor’s attempt to face that delicate part of her. The drum beats build a looming anxiety that lasts for the entirety of the track, creating an anticipation for climax, yet never reaching a cathartic moment. By depicting the uncertainty inherent to love, the song also reminds us that uncertainty is simply a fact of life, that things often do not have definitive ends, that somethings just become forgotten, trail off, and reach nowhere.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In that achingly sad moment of introspection, Taylor becomes aware of her shattered self as the veneers peeled away — she realizes that anyone can see right through her, just as she sings “I see right through me.” As the weariness finally washes over, the desperation for someone to stick around this time highlights precisely how there is no guarantee of it. After half a decade of jumping from romances, she understands that love stories are not as simple as “baby just say yes.” They may be complicated, messy, and inconclusive. Fairytales do not exist in real life, and if you want something, you have to fight for it — whether it be truth, vindication, or love.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;a-grand-forgiveness&quot;&gt;A Grand Forgiveness&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I guess the lesson &lt;em&gt;Lover&lt;/em&gt; brings is knowing ourselves. Understanding our own fragility makes us more accepting of others. Understanding our own defects makes us braver and more honest. “I Forgot That You Existed,” with playful and light presentation, contrasts greatly against the dark, gothic tracks from reputation. “It’s Nice To Have A Friend,” is the other side to “This Is Why We Can’t Have Nice Things.” Through a celebration of love and passion, she has learned to forgive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As dramas of the past dissipate, as the happy, the unhappy, the fortunate, and the unfortunate fade, Taylor Swift, in the spirit of moving on, bathes in “Daylight” and proclaims that “I wanna be defined by the things that I love. Not the things I hate. Not the things I’m afraid of, or the things that haunt me in the middle of the night.” She cannot remain America’s Sweetheart forever. Nobody can. Just like Rihanna’s modeling career and Gaga’s makeup line, there comes a time for Taylor to find her own voice. This time around, Taylor Swift announces that she will not be defined by resentment or snake emojis. Instead, she would like to be remembered by forgiveness, self-care, and maturity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everyone makes mistakes. We can all be seized by vengeance and rage. But more importantly, we also grow up, encounter ourselves, and find the things that matter more. Leaving the bad in the past — that is the victor’s attitude. Being defined by what you love — that is &lt;em&gt;Lover&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Music" /><category term="Taylor Swift" /><category term="Pop" /><category term="Featured" /><summary type="html">We all remember the vengeful spirit of Taylor Swift. From claiming that “there’s nothing I do better than revenge” to “bandaids don’t fix bullet holes,” a certain part of her discography was dedicated to feuds and lost loves. Just two years ago, Taylor can be seen burning bridges and throwing shades, (in addition to being presumably dead) in the music video for “Look What You Made Me Do.”</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Crazy Rich Asians: Socioeconomic Mismatch and The Farewell</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/crazy-rich-asians" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Crazy Rich Asians&amp;#58; Socioeconomic Mismatch and The Farewell" /><published>2019-08-03T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2019-08-03T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/crazy-rich</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/crazy-rich-asians">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Crazy Rich Asians&lt;/em&gt; is a movie that got many things right. The drama is great (albeit unrealistic at times), the performances by Constance Wu, Awkwafina, and Michelle Yeoh (soon debuting her own &lt;em&gt;Star Trek&lt;/em&gt; series!) are outstanding, the soundtrack — with heavy Asian-influenced curation (particularly the mandarin version of Yellow) — is touching. But it is also a movie that got a couple of key things wrong, and those significant flaws result in an identity crisis that diminishes the overall message.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://media1.s-nbcnews.com/i/newscms/2018_35/2543511/180824-crazy-rich-asians-al-1708_5a509f4d2866590468f39a0b86679796.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Cover&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;socioeconomic-mismatch&quot;&gt;Socioeconomic Mismatch&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I loved everything until Rachel boards the plane back to NYC. It’s perfect, and the mahjong scene brought me to tears. However, with the ending, the movie proceeds to dive off a 200-meter skyscraper. Here’s the thing, Rachel and Nick should NOT have ended up together. They don’t belong together — this is not my personal hot take, but a logical conclusion the film itself suggests.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the film, Astrid and Michael, a couple with great socioeconomic disparity, much like Rachel and Nick, end horribly with extramarital affairs and blame games. It serves as a premonition for all of us to consider socioeconomic forces as a potent disrupter in marriage, and sends a message to the audience that is in direct conflict with Rachel and Nick’s ending. Love can seem wonderful on paper, but marriage, as a union between two families, two upbringings, two ideologies, two cultures, is not the same. There are bound to be differences and obstacles, and what &lt;em&gt;Crazy Rich Asians&lt;/em&gt; seems to suggest, at least with Astrid and Michael, is that differences in wealth and background leads to an imbalance between the two parties, which eventually wears off the romance and passion, which eventually makes Michael feel inferior and sensitive and makes Astrid hide the jewels she loves that she bought with her own money. Under such premise of irreconcilable socioeconomic differences, how are we supposed to believe that Rachel and Nick will be any different? The story’s treatment of Astrid and Michael foreshadows what might be in store for Nick and Rachel, and if so, I’d rather have them miss each other than suffer an insufferable marriage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/08/crazy-rich-asians-gemma-chan.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Cover&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What we have to understand, is that although Rachel is modeled as the 21st century Cinderella, the plot should not be confined to the imagination of Cinderella. Rachel Chu is a self-made, modern woman and a professor at a world-renowned university — she represents the power of self-reliance. She deserves her own career, her own life, not living under someone else’s roof, subordinate to other people’s superiority. In this way, the film’s presentation of independence and individuality is confusing at best, and self-contradicting at worst.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When she goes back with Nick, underneath the glamor of the engagement party, there still exists the disdain, the supremacy deep in the bones of the elites who will never accept her and never see her as their equal. Nick’s insistence cannot suddenly change everyone’s mind, and Rachel will have to suffer the insincerity and hypocrisy of the elites forever. They might greet her, they might be nice to her, but both Rachel and they know that she will never be one of them. This is near-character assassination of Rachel. She’s presented as an earnest and pure soul, so why she would willingly subject herself to the eyerolls and being looked down on, for the rest of her life, I couldn’t possibly fathom.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;cultural-identity&quot;&gt;Cultural Identity&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aside from that, the all-Asian cast is commendable: it shows what multicultural representation in Hollywood and in the international media consumption market could look like. However, from a cultural perspective, the message of the film is less empowering. Essentially, the story presents a war of ideological values between the pan-Asian family-first culture and the Western desire for individual liberation. At its core, the film seems to be praising the Western way of life and derogatory towards the Eastern one, painting it as the antagonist. The set location, even, is Singapore, a place with historically significant colonial influence and westernized allegiance. The old money Crazy Rich Asians of the film still have to fortify a colonial facade with a good-enough-British-accent or the British-style-of-life. All of this seems not just blatantly inaccurate of the mainstream way of life, but also socially wrong.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://a468ba3fc2be117c5560-f9a6225d634730495a59b91d1543c5a4.ssl.cf5.rackcdn.com/_still/farewell-thumb-new2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Cover&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the contrary, &lt;em&gt;The Farewell&lt;/em&gt;, the 2019 title directed by Lulu Wang, portrays the family-first value of East Asian countries more accurately. The family wants the grandma to live her last days in peace, so everyone agrees to act in unison to protect her precious joy. There are no grand gestures, no luxurious setting, the shots are more commonplace, yet they strike with force more poignant than &lt;em&gt;Crazy Rich Asians&lt;/em&gt;, probably because &lt;em&gt;The Farewell&lt;/em&gt; is less about the idealized version of Asian life, and more about the elements of Asianness that affects a broader audience. The more unbiased presentation makes it more human.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I guess the takeaway is that Asians are cool and beautiful and smart, whether Constance Wu or Awkwafina, whether Rachel or Billi. There is nothing wrong with Asianness, there is nothing wrong with valuing one’s family — they are things we should embrace, and over the course of year, I’ve learned to embrace. There is no denying that &lt;em&gt;Crazy Rich Asians&lt;/em&gt; is a good movie, and that &lt;em&gt;The Farewell&lt;/em&gt; is a great movie, and both of them bring multicultural representation into the cinematic conversation. And I hope that with growing confidence of Asians everywhere, there will be more productions like these on the big screen.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Movie" /><summary type="html">Crazy Rich Asians is a movie that got many things right. The drama is great (albeit unrealistic at times), the performances by Constance Wu, Awkwafina, and Michelle Yeoh (soon debuting her own Star Trek series!) are outstanding, the soundtrack — with heavy Asian-influenced curation (particularly the mandarin version of Yellow) — is touching. But it is also a movie that got a couple of key things wrong, and those significant flaws result in an identity crisis that diminishes the overall message.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Russian Doll: It’s Hard to Stay Alive</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/russian-doll" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Russian Doll&amp;#58; It's Hard to Stay Alive" /><published>2019-06-24T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2019-06-24T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/russian-doll</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/russian-doll">&lt;p&gt;You would think that after an entire school year of Nietzsche, Meursault, Godot, Kafka, Hemingway, and &lt;em&gt;Like Water for Chocolate&lt;/em&gt; in International Baccalaureate English would be enough absurdist discussion for a while, if not an entire lifetime. But &lt;em&gt;Russian Doll&lt;/em&gt;, the extremely odd, extremely beautiful, and extremely thought-provoking delight, proved to be just that piece of existentialism I never knew I needed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The sheer brilliance in the editing and cinematography is just the least of it: the message is what I find to be the most interesting. Particularly, the message that “it’s too easy to die that it’s hard to stay alive.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The series is deeply absurd, with the protagonist running into death in the most unexpected, dark-humor ways — at times, it’s nearly the real life version of Dumb Ways To Die. It’s also deeply existential, with a beautifully-crafted dialogue on which parts of the numerous ways to die actually convey the essence of life. It’s a story about two equally unfortunate people finding their own meaning of existence, and somehow that’s incredibly grand and moving.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;nadias-dilemma&quot;&gt;Nadia’s Dilemma&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Time passes by linearly throughout the show, but the main character, Nadia, is stuck on the night of her birthday party — the recycled moments of her waking up in front of the bathroom mirror is a diametric symbol of death and rebirth. Nadia and the other protagonist, Alan, theorized that the seemingly eternal time-loop is a punishment for their mistakes during their childhood. Nadia wanted to leave her mother, and attributed her mother’s death to her own fault, after which she decided to push other people away to avoid any possibility of genuine connection that might end up hurting both parties.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But through the eyes of Ruth, Nadia’s life-long friend and mentor, it was never Nadia’s fault. She was a tiny seed buried in darkness fighting her way to the light. She wanted to &lt;em&gt;live&lt;/em&gt;, and “it’s the most beautiful thing in the world.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As Ruth speaks arguably the most touching line of the series: “Do you still have that in you? I look at you now, chasing down death at every corner. Sweetheart, where is that gorgeous piece of you pushing to be a part of this world?” Nadia tears up, as would anyone who has felt the powerlessness of barely living, day to day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nadia is not a completely good person. Sometimes she’s not kind enough, or proactive enough, or friendly enough — she knows that about herself, so while she’s unforgiving of everything around her, that cynical attitude also extends to herself. She would appear tough, nonchalant, totally untouchable, absolutely inconsiderate, the consequences of which include a deep feeling of isolation and emptiness that can not be cured by the alcohol, or random sexual encounters, or an israeli-joint-highlighted birthday party.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Perhaps that’s her defense mechanism, of closing herself off from the world, thus eliminating the possibility of getting hurt and hurting other people. Or perhaps that’s who we all are — &lt;em&gt;incompletely good&lt;/em&gt; — as a result of our tendency to avoid pain and discomfort. But may I suggest to you that the experiences of bruising, the pain inherent to love, hate, and betrayal are the most real, human things, and that when we insulate ourselves from the world, we lose parts of what make us human in the first place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/law-wang/moodblog/master/assets/images/RD2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Cover&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;it-is-not-the-end&quot;&gt;It Is Not The End&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The ending is a beautiful moment. It has a quality that is as promising as &lt;em&gt;Groundhog Day&lt;/em&gt;, but not quite &lt;em&gt;Groundhog Day&lt;/em&gt;. The two protagonists reappear in front of their bathroom mirrors one last time and realize they are in different dimensions — the other person is back in cycle #1 and has no recollection of the death-defying adventures they shared together. Now, they have to look for the other person and convince them that all those hundreds of attempts at living and dying were actually real. As the screen splits in half, the audience witnesses a hopeful Alan assisting the turbulent Nadia, and a patient Nadia comforting the confused Alan. And as they walk through the winter New York streets, the two screens merge into one, with a renewed Nadia holding a torch, finally, again, pushing to be a part of this world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes, the mediocrity of daily chores and the pressures from expectations can make life feel like hell, like purgatory on earth. Sometimes, the anxiety of being alive strikes blows to us that seem impossible to handle. But as &lt;em&gt;Russian Doll&lt;/em&gt; reminds us, &lt;strong&gt;we are not alone in this world&lt;/strong&gt;. We still have each other, can find each other, and save each other. Just like in the ending when Nadia and Alan march, joining Horse’s parade of monsters, passing the shoulders of their alternative selves — &lt;em&gt;they have not given up on each other&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The world out there can be a vile one. A lonely one. A troubled one. One in which it’s hard to stay alive. But if we can all dig into our hearts, see ourselves for who we are, and learn to forgive and reconcile, maybe we can also let go of the cold, exoskeletal shells of protective covers; let go of the habit of keeping people at a distance; let go of the need to hide our insecurities and conceal our mistakes. In doing so, perhaps we might rediscover the fine world that is worth fighting for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;May this newfound hope and companionship in &lt;em&gt;Russian Doll&lt;/em&gt; mean that the past moments of “I just want to die” are not the end.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Television" /><category term="Netflix" /><category term="Featured" /><summary type="html">You would think that after an entire school year of Nietzsche, Meursault, Godot, Kafka, Hemingway, and Like Water for Chocolate in International Baccalaureate English would be enough absurdist discussion for a while, if not an entire lifetime. But Russian Doll, the extremely odd, extremely beautiful, and extremely thought-provoking delight, proved to be just that piece of existentialism I never knew I needed.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Nocturnal Girl and Gone Animals: A Comparison</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/gone-girl-nocturnal-animals" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Nocturnal Girl and Gone Animals&amp;#58; A Comparison" /><published>2018-07-22T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2018-07-22T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/nocturnal-animals-gone-girl</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/gone-girl-nocturnal-animals">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Gone Girl&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Nocturnal Animals&lt;/em&gt; — released two years apart, one by the legendary David Fincher, the other by the fashion mongol Tom Ford — are strikingly similar in many ways. Both contain wonderful shots, such as when Ben Affleck’s fingers run through Rosamund Pike’s hair and when Amy Adams stands in front of the mirror in her green dress as A Table For Two plays in the background. &lt;em&gt;Gone Girl&lt;/em&gt; describes the aftermath of a girl losing the perfect guy she was promised, whereas &lt;em&gt;Nocturnal Animals&lt;/em&gt; describes that of a guy losing his wife and child. Now, maybe Tom Ford’s use of color and treatment of silence makes his work the more artsy of the two, but we should all be able to agree that the two share a common discussion of love and revenge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;two-perspectives&quot;&gt;Two Perspectives&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The two films are conducted through different characters. In &lt;em&gt;Gone Girl&lt;/em&gt;, Nick is introduced first, and the mystery about his missing wife, Amy, unfolds from his perspective; in &lt;em&gt;Nocturnal Animals&lt;/em&gt;, Susan reads the manuscripts that her ex-husband, Edward, sent her and recounts her story. The differences in perspectives give rise to different allegiances and sympathies for the audience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nick and Amy are inmates trapped in the prison of marriage, which sucks dry their love and strips away their romantic fantasies. They loved different things: Amy loved the Prince Charming and wasn’t aware that he’s actually lazy and uninspired; Nick loved the Cool Girl and wasn’t aware that she can be overbearing yet forbearant, arrogant yet timid, cold-hearted yet warm-blooded, self-loathing yet determined. One of them has to lose for the other to win.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Edward’s manuscripts, Tony Hasting, the autobiographical protagonist, conducts an immaculate revenge. Tony suffers and plots and kills because for him, love and hate are disparate emotions directed at different people. He loves his wife and daughter, and he has to kill Ray Marcus to avenge his wife and child. In Susan and Edward’s marriage, however, it’s not so clear: Susan is Edward’s wife &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; archnemesis: she is both the love of his life and the one who brutally killed the love of his life. In fact, the Susan that Edward loves had been long dead. She died once in the hands of Ray Marcus. She died another time when she told Edward: “I am a realist. I am happy.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.mos.cms.futurecdn.net/CRbRhtoz5tR3fFR4o3ExxX.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Cover&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;role-of-society&quot;&gt;Role of Society&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The story of &lt;em&gt;Gone Girl&lt;/em&gt; starts as economic pressures breaks the perfect pretense, as Nick becomes dull and tired of playing the ideal husband, and ends as social pressure reforges a broken marriage, as Nick chooses to give in and Amy gets what she wants. Amy has a dream, a style of life she would do anything to defend, whether it be “being raped” or “being murdered.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In &lt;em&gt;Nocturnal Animals&lt;/em&gt;, the key conflict can be boiled down to the socioeconomic disparities between Susan and Edward. Susan comes from a wealthy background, and although a liberal education has given her understanding for different classes and appreciation of values beyond material, it has not changed her mentality that favors basic economic security. She could not give up the comforts that she had grown accustomed to, and when Edward fails to provide that, Susan becomes who she dreads the most — her mother.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As such, the social construct is a common factor in both tragedies. One shatters the American Dream with its nuclear-family-happiness and exposes the hypocrisy of middle class elites who indulge in intricate illusions out of boredom and encourage media carnivals after every borderline societal crisis. The other one confirms the doom of socioeconomic mismatch even in a society where the effects of such are said to be negligible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://badgerherald.com/wordpress/wp-content/uploads/2014/10/gone-girl-01_1485x612.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Cover&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;no-one-comes-out-clean&quot;&gt;No One Comes Out Clean&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When Prince Charming is no longer and Cool Girl becomes Gone Girl, the two have to collect their wreck of a marriage and carry on. Cool Girl does not care about the delicateness of a marriage, she acts with minimal considerations of the circumstances because she knows she’s smarter than the rest of them. She cried, demanded, threatened, provoked. She taints herself with blood. She uses anyone and everyone she could. By doing so, she ends up securing the illusory love and marriage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What she never considers is that, perhaps, she doesn’t need to be the cool girl, and Nick doesn’t have to be a model husband, her life can be saved from the lies. But no, that’s not what the Gone Girl wants. Truth? Happiness? Who cares. It’s only for show anyway.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Nocturnal Animals&lt;/em&gt; carries the opposite message. It tells us that when you love someone, you have to be careful with it because once you break it, you might never get back it again, just like how Susan sits in the restaurant waiting for Edward who will never show. They meet, mess each other’s lives up, and have to live forever knowing what they could have had. In other words, they don’t need to meet again because even though they once loved each other, they both know Susan loves herself more. &lt;em&gt;When it comes to love, everyone is to blame.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Movie" /><category term="Tom Ford" /><category term="David Fincher" /><summary type="html">Gone Girl and Nocturnal Animals — released two years apart, one by the legendary David Fincher, the other by the fashion mongol Tom Ford — are strikingly similar in many ways. Both contain wonderful shots, such as when Ben Affleck’s fingers run through Rosamund Pike’s hair and when Amy Adams stands in front of the mirror in her green dress as A Table For Two plays in the background. Gone Girl describes the aftermath of a girl losing the perfect guy she was promised, whereas Nocturnal Animals describes that of a guy losing his wife and child. Now, maybe Tom Ford’s use of color and treatment of silence makes his work the more artsy of the two, but we should all be able to agree that the two share a common discussion of love and revenge.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Melodrama: The Glamour and Trauma Became Us</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/melodrama" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Melodrama&amp;#58; The Glamour and Trauma Became Us" /><published>2018-06-05T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2018-06-05T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/melodrama</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/melodrama">&lt;p&gt;If &lt;em&gt;Pure Heroine&lt;/em&gt; was about teenage Lorde’s idea of maturity, her imagination of what the adult world must be like, then her sophomore album is precisely the opposite. &lt;em&gt;Melodrama&lt;/em&gt; is cool— the toned quality materializes through the predominantly blue album art. And with this record, the brilliant facade of the adult world peels off layer by layer, until all that’s left is the delicate, jaded, melancholic core.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jack Antonoff’s production adds another coating of complexity and unforgettable projection to Lorde’s end-of-adolescence state of mind: the youth slipping away on the light-up floor, the secluded utopia of careless parties, the love that burns so bright and then breaks into pieces. It touches the solemn and fateful side of this initiation rite of adulthood.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;a-never-ending-party&quot;&gt;A Never-Ending Party&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now if &lt;em&gt;Melodrama&lt;/em&gt; were a party, then Green Light marks the start of the journey of a “drunk girl at the party dancing around crying about her ex-boyfriend who everyone thinks is a mess.” The lead single has such a sense of finality to it, opening the album with a mysterious, cool-colored yet charming story of a new beginning. The mindless carousing continues even though no one knows what might happen when they’re Sober. Or perhaps “pretending that we don’t care” is just another part of adulthood? After all, “going astray with me” is only an attitude to life. Yes, leaving in the morning will hurt, hearts will ache, but why not take this moment to dance with us? Perhaps losing a bit of our minds will be good for us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Liability is the turning point, the moment of self-reflective weakness. In the dead of night, as the party continues, we go off to the bathroom and see ourselves in the mirror— the terrible, mess of a self. And we realize the horrifying, underlying truth— what exactly does it take to grow up? Compromising our identity? Exposing the most delicate parts ourselves to the devouring of others? That’s when the revelation comes so strikingly poignant: as the lights turn on and the people go home, as we lose ourselves in the distrust and cold-shoulder of others, as the youthful part of ourselves, the innocent dreams of past time depart and fade away in the waters borne ceaselessly into the past, what do we have left?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, love and breakups are quintessential to any grow up story. The remarkable romanticism of the album is apparent in The Louvre through the literary devices: the personification of summer, the days and nights that are “perfumed” with obsession present the beauty of an endearing love. Yet as suggested by the uneasy beats of the track, that beauty, so alarmingly coated in sacrifice, eventually will fall apart. With the somber recount of the aftermath of the break up in Hard Feelings, we are introduced to the winter, the death of the rushing feelings that were once so strong, so domineering, so relentless. Ultimately, as comfortable as being underneath summer’s tongue was, there comes a day when we all have to let go of that endless summer afternoon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;from-the-end-of-one-to-the-start-of-another&quot;&gt;From the End of One to the Start of Another&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The theme is then reinforced through Sober II (Melodrama) and Writer In The Dark. The love ends, romance is succeeded by melodrama. In the blinding fumes of accusations, we realize that we always knew we would end up here; it’s only in the psycho-high kind of self-indulgence did we forget that:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;They’ll talk about us, all the lovers&lt;br /&gt;
How we kiss and kill each other.&lt;br /&gt;
They’ll talk about us, and discover&lt;br /&gt;
How we kissed and killed each other.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yet we can’t help but reminiscing the magic and love and tender touches in the car that characterized the summertimes, before the blizzard hit the town and we had to board up the windows and retreat into solitude. And in that contemplation, we arrive at the conclusion:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;All of the dreams that get harder,&lt;br /&gt;
All of the things that I offer you,&lt;br /&gt;
All of the shit that we harbour,&lt;br /&gt;
But you’re not what you thought you were.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So in the grand finale, we dump it all away in Perfect Places. In a sense, this last track summarizes the entire story, from the party to the fragility, from the love to no-more-love. In the graceless night, we are wild and young for the one last time. &lt;em&gt;Dancing. Proclaiming we are all-right. Yelling to the heavens, trying to prove the perfect place that doesn’t exist.&lt;/em&gt; We try to get there, but we never will. We are doomed to fail, but we carry on. And isn’t precisely this kind of valor, of trying in spite of challenges that is so admirable about the transition from adolescence into adulthood?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;melodrama-and-us&quot;&gt;Melodrama and Us&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The album is titled melodrama, romance love affairs. Yet the album is not simply about breaking up, or even love. It seems closer to a diary to oneself, about how to manage the solitude, how to understand the ever-so complex notion of self— all of that, wrapped in strong sonic and lyrical cohesion. This is a part of why I was absolutely dumbfounded when &lt;em&gt;Melodrama&lt;/em&gt; was snubbed of its album of the year. The journey Lorde presents shows the audience a meditation on the loneliness of an ambitious pop drama queen. The intimate vocals, lyrics, productions here are all Grammy’s worthy— yet all of that paled in face of the 60th Annual Grammy Awards’ pursuit of “equality” and “representation.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Above all, the fragility of breakups, the confusion of growing up, the depravity of carousing, the loneliness of sobriety, the fiery emotions of adulthood— &lt;em&gt;Melodrama&lt;/em&gt; contains all of these. And through editing life into one endless party, the good, the bad, the glamour, the trauma all invariably arrive at who we are.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lorde’s idea of youth is acute, indulging, complete and unconditional. So many melodrama will end up being supercuts. So many hard feelings will lead to exclamation of what the fuck are perfect places. Perhaps this youth is imperfect, but its stubborn, tenacious, yet sinister vitality is precious and impossible to compound.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Music" /><category term="Lorde" /><category term="Pop" /><category term="sticky" /><summary type="html">If Pure Heroine was about teenage Lorde’s idea of maturity, her imagination of what the adult world must be like, then her sophomore album is precisely the opposite. Melodrama is cool— the toned quality materializes through the predominantly blue album art. And with this record, the brilliant facade of the adult world peels off layer by layer, until all that’s left is the delicate, jaded, melancholic core.</summary></entry></feed>