<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.0.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-03-29T10:59:50-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Lawrence Wang</title><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title type="html">Corona, College, and Us</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/corona" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Corona, College, and Us" /><published>2020-03-20T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2020-03-20T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/corona</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/corona">&lt;p&gt;The problematic thing about an international public health emergency that forces the closure of schools, restaurants, and social events, aside from the fact that I’ve been rotting away at home and can’t even find solace in the slim chance that I might be able to go to Glastonbury over the summer since both Glastonbury and London and my study abroad program are likely cancelled, is the fact that I can’t even listen to music in peace anymore. I’ve always found it interesting, the way we are conditioned to associate certain memories with music and how they evoke the same emotional and conscious response every time, but never have I found it so infuriating. So many song in my Spotify library have such distinct moments written across them that it becomes impossible to listen to practically anything without wondering, with the utmost confusion, where did my freshman year go?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;cruel-summer&quot;&gt;Cruel Summer&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Lover&lt;/em&gt; dropped while I was digging holes to defecate in and hating my life in the Appalachian wilderness, so I did not get to hear the album first hand. But I did the moment I got my lovely T-Mobile 4G LTE network back, and on the bus from New Hampshire to Connecticut I heard it and fell asleep. The standout from the album, and what absolutely should have been the lead single, was Cruel Summer, a song that combines everything I loved in the New Romantics - Getaway Car trajectory.  Now, it reminds me of Camp Yale So. Damn. Much. When I listen to it I can hear my own yearning in those early college days, the hope for some exquisite chance encounter to befall upon me, the days in New Haven when it was warm enough for shorts — I can feel the breeze blowing by my legs. It makes me think of lying in the Silliman courtyard, walking down Wall Street for another info session, going to Starbucks to get a venti water and keeping the cup for the whole month because it had a straw, sitting in the common room of people whose world views you weren’t sure aligned with yours and yet, at that moment, you were just happy to be there. Cruel Summer is inclusion and strangeness, excitement and fear, hope and the aftermath when bubbles of hope are popped one by one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;california&quot;&gt;California&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Though written about wanting someone back, California is when sadness seeps through the semi-permeable membrane you’ve built to guard yourself. “You’re scared to win, scared to lose. I’ve heard the war was over if you really choose” reminds me of the light drizzles that occupied New Haven’s winter, and walking down Hillhouse in midst of the rain without an umbrella. The moments when nostalgia rushes to my head and says: California, In-N-Out, Sprouts, Brown Cow, Sharetea, they melted with academic burdens that seem like nothing in retrospect, but were suffocating at the time, in Lana’s slow murmuring.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;beautiful-ghosts&quot;&gt;Beautiful Ghosts&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had been anticipating this release for more than a month, ever since hearing the 10 second clip in Cats promotion — a movie I was actually hoping to see but never did because I got scared after reading the reviews. Well, at least the song turned out to be great and made me cry that Friday at 1 A.M. In the coming weeks I blasted the song in the common room so many times that all my suite mates grew tired of it. Today it still gives me chills, especially the “I never knew I’d love this world they’ve let me into” moment, which makes me think of all the internship rejections I received, in addition to wondering about spending the summer in London, which is no longer happening so idk who I was kidding.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;light-on&quot;&gt;Light On&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I first discovered &lt;em&gt;Heard It In A Past Life&lt;/em&gt; I thought I found a gem: Maggie Rogers’s debut was sensational and genuine. Now when I listen to it I see New York. I see the time we ate hot pot and got Boba Guys on the TD sponsored trip, and how we had to scuffle our way through the Times Square crowd to catch the bus. I see the Old Navy in Midtown, the Ding Tea, and the Shake Shack in Grand Central. I think of that one night in New York, when I was planning on staying at NYU until I learned about their stupid policy regarding overnight guests, at which point I decided I would take a 1-hour subway ride uptown at 1 A.M. and completely embarrass myself by entering my friend’s apartment complex, looking assured about where I’m headed because I did not want to interact with the lobby staff, and walking into a random elevator that, as it turns out, did not go to his floor. There was also no signal in the building, so I had to wander around the third floor for 30 minutes before I found another elevator. I woke up the next morning at 7, and sat down at a nearby Starbucks thinking: “Wow, this must be what college is like.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another time, after briefly stopping by the NYU Weinstein lounge where Chinese international students were playing mafia until 3 A.M., I walked to the 8th Street Station to get to JFK for my 8 A.M. flight. There was not a single soul in the station, so instead of waiting on the empty, eerie platform for the N train which never came, I dragged my suitcases up the stairs into the rain. It was cold. I was alone. My bags were drenched. But I enjoyed having the streets to myself — it felt regal, and I liked how the lights were blurred by downpour, then reflected by puddles, then shattered by droplets hitting the surface. &lt;strong&gt;Light On reminds me of the rain that night.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;if-the-world-was-ending&quot;&gt;If the World Was Ending&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I love the first line of the song “I was distracted and in traffic, I didn’t feel it when the earthquake happened” because I don’t feel earthquakes when I’m in cars, except for that one time when I did, after which I drove to Urban Outfitters and got boba. The song makes me think of staying at friends’ suite until late, watching them dance to Super Bass, eating McDonald’s and getting stomach cramps afterwards. Now, although my freshman year is in shambles, school is shut down, borders are closed, I still don’t want to forget anything that happened because it was one of those remarkable moments in time when everything felt exciting; and here’s a customary Taylor Swift quote: “We’re all really sad that this is ending, but we’re really happy because of what it was.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the death toll becoming more and more “just a number,” the hysterical shopping for toilet paper, the staying at home and not getting Chick-fil-A or tofu for months to come, I reckon it feels pretty much like the end of the world. But trust, though I might not be able to get out of my house arrest to stay the night, that it will be fine — corona is not down for forever anyway.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Personal" /><category term="Reflection" /><category term="Featured" /><summary type="html">The problematic thing about an international public health emergency that forces the closure of schools, restaurants, and social events, aside from the fact that I’ve been rotting away at home and can’t even find solace in the slim chance that I might be able to go to Glastonbury over the summer since both Glastonbury and London and my study abroad program are likely cancelled, is the fact that I can’t even listen to music in peace anymore. I’ve always found it interesting, the way we are conditioned to associate certain memories with music and how they evoke the same emotional and conscious response every time, but never have I found it so infuriating. So many song in my Spotify library have such distinct moments written across them that it becomes impossible to listen to practically anything without wondering, with the utmost confusion, where did my freshman year go?</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Suburbia</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/suburbia" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Suburbia" /><published>2020-01-23T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2020-01-23T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/suburbia</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/suburbia">&lt;p&gt;When it comes to goodbyes, I’m experienced, or so I thought. Last summer, I said goodbye to skipping school for a Starbucks run under the 90-degree California sun. Before that, I said goodbye to lunch under woven canopies that never stopped the rain from wetting our food. Further back, I said goodbye to the comforts of motherland and native tongue. Moving across the country for college? It’ll be a piece of cake, I told myself as I hugged my brother and bid farewell to my parents. Before I knew it, I was out the door.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Arriving was disorienting to say the least: the chaos, the welcomes, the dragging-suitcases-across-campus, the unfamiliar faces. Everything was new and strange. The Vineyard Vines, the way people say “bubble tea” instead of “boba,” the fact that Shake Shack, instead of McDonald’s, takes center stage in the town, the sheer number of people from &lt;em&gt;New Jersey&lt;/em&gt;. New, for sure. But exciting also, right?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the time, I agreed. New is good, different is good, and sentimentality is overrated, I thought. But as I lay in a tarp tent on the First-Year Outdoor Orientation Trip, I was overcome by a sudden longing. Newness became fear, and fear graduated into longing for home. I started to miss a lot of things. The nights when Dad sat in front of his computer, crossing off items on a list: ropes for climbing, boots for hiking, sprays for bug bites, down jacket for winter, bedding that must be Egyptian cotton with 800 thread count. Some of them from Amazon, some of them brought all the way across the ocean in family friends’ suitcases. The warm smell of the tofu fried pork belly embellished with vibrant green pepper, and Mom knew just the amount of spice to add without having me chug down potsful of water. The way Dad walked by my desk at exactly midnight with a palmful of vitamins before he went to bed because he knew I always forget them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During my last couple days at home, Dad kept repeating how “by the time you leave for college, you will have already spent 93% of the time you will ever spend with us.” I didn’t pay much mind to it then, I thought it’s a moment worth celebrating, a new page. I wanted to commemorate it, not to let the end dim the sparkle of the story. But when I was enthralled by the new, what I always seem to forget is how much I rely on the old.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the first night of elementary school when all the kids were scrambling out of the dorm and screaming playing jump rope on the moonlit field, I pulled the teacher aside and pointed to the apartment building barely visible behind layers of leaves and said “look, that’s my home.” Weren’t my eyes teary then? On one of the first nights in the U.S., after coming back from Denny’s and trash-talking American food, I sat on the balcony of our new house and sighed “this doesn’t feel like home” and how Mom looked up at the blank ceiling, her smile forced and bitter. It didn’t feel like home to her either.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We always took on the shifts and goodbyes in life together, me and my family. In elementary school, nights in the dorm were lonely, but every weekend, I went home. Then we would drive across the city to East Lake, where there’d be cherry blossoms by the pagoda in the spring and water lilies roaming the surface in the summer. When we first moved to L.A., we endured the miscommunications with the water meter together, the unwilling-to-engage with The Home Depot employees together, the too-afraid-to-order at restaurants together. And until that common denominator was ripped away from me, I never quite grasped the value of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the final get-together with my high school friends, we watched &lt;em&gt;The Farewell&lt;/em&gt;. My favorite scene was the ending, when Awkwafina stops in the middle of the busy New York street and shouts at the top of her lungs. The sound ripples all the way back to her hometown in China, scaring a flock of birds out of the tree by her grandma’s house. It makes me wonder sometimes, when I scream in the shower hoping none of my floormates notice, would my family hear me? Is Mom tending to her succulents? Is Dad compulsively wringing the clothes out of the washing machine for the fifth time? Are they alright?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But isn’t that the beauty of growing up? You become more and more alone until you’re all that’s left on the road. When I was young, I thought I could be anything, Premier of the State Council, CEO of a Fortune 500, scientist discovering the next big thing, until I realized I could be none of those. Because at the time, I didn’t know I would volunteer at two research labs and end up abhorring both, I didn’t know my dad was detained by the Communist Party for two months under false allegations, I didn’t know I missed the recruitment mark for my elementary school by two points and wouldn’t have been able to attend if not for the 5,000 yuan my mom gave to her friend with a connection.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It sounds like a grim world, but I’d say growing up is not necessarily the process of discovering a darker world. At seven-years-old, everything was shiny and splendid. Now I realize it seemed magical and wonderful because back then, everything was simple. The people who love me shielded me from the complex, the blurry, the despicable. The world is neither intensely beautiful nor extremely horrible. It’s just difficult and complicated, and neither the good nor the bad present the whole truth. I’ve learned that growing up is accepting the complicated world, accepting the gap between reality and expectation, and still choosing to believe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I guess you always start off wide-eyed about everything. But the novelty wears off as soon as you come to the realization that any stranger you lay your eyes on the street might have a totally unique story, a story that might remain a mystery to you forever. You realize the planet is filled to its brink with extraordinary people doing all sorts of things. That’s why you would, while traversing the vast and lonely world, reminisce more furiously about the &lt;em&gt;suburbia&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nostalgia really is a funny thing. Most days, you don’t pay much mind to it. But at unexpected times, under unexpected circumstances, it would revolt, charge, attack with power beyond description, and leave you with insurmountable strength. Then it fades and hibernates for its next spring. Nowadays when I go home, I get reprimanded less for waking up too late or staying out too late or eating too much In-N-Out. It’s good. Different and good. I also get phone calls from home. I dread them sometimes because I know Mom would be pressing me to join Club Swimming, or badminton, or go to calligraphy class, things that I inherently hate or refuse to find the time to do. But it’s ok, it’s all love, I tell myself. It’s all love.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Personal" /><category term="Reflection" /><category term="Featured" /><summary type="html">When it comes to goodbyes, I’m experienced, or so I thought. Last summer, I said goodbye to skipping school for a Starbucks run under the 90-degree California sun. Before that, I said goodbye to lunch under woven canopies that never stopped the rain from wetting our food. Further back, I said goodbye to the comforts of motherland and native tongue. Moving across the country for college? It’ll be a piece of cake, I told myself as I hugged my brother and bid farewell to my parents. Before I knew it, I was out the door.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The 2019</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2019" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The 2019" /><published>2019-12-31T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2019-12-31T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2019</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2019">&lt;p&gt;What did the 2010s mean to you? What do you remember? Late night procrastination, chilling watching television? Walking to Starbucks after school, walking to school from Starbucks? Crying when opening the college admissions portal, crying with the shower running only to be heard by your parents anyway? Was it a nightmare, a mad trip, a flavored kool-aid? Was it existential, or empty, or cold, sometimes lonely? Golden? like a Ferrari on Mulholland drive?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The 2010s was the first full decade I’ve lived through, the first through which I tracked every single movie I watched, the first during which I started making bimonthly playlists. It’s also when I got my first personal computer, when I created my first enter-the-name-of-every-single-social-media-platform account, and when I initiated first contact with the internet, games, music, movies — essentially the beginning of my life as a screenager.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Life had been completely revolutionized in the 10s: I started the decade wandering around Disneyland Paris without knowing a single word of French; one second I was preparing for my middle school entrance exam in Wuhan, the next I was sitting in a classroom speaking broken English in a suburban school in California; I ended the decade with no knowledge of Spanish other than a damned 4 on the AP Spanish test. I regretted not going to The 1989 World Tour; I sang along to Team without knowing any other song from &lt;em&gt;Pure Heroine&lt;/em&gt; which would become the love of my life; I hated &lt;em&gt;Bloom&lt;/em&gt;, then liked &lt;em&gt;Bloom&lt;/em&gt;; I hated Sam Smith, then loved him, then hated him again for not singing the title track on his tour; I wiggled my way around art, though never finding out exactly what I love; I moved from imagining to making, from collecting floor plans to not having time to collect floor plans, from reading Chinese books to reading English books back to reading Chinese books.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 2013, when &lt;em&gt;Frozen&lt;/em&gt; first came out, I must’ve seen that movie at least 10 times because every single teacher would play it at school when they had nothing else for us to do. Let It Go became a cultural phenomenon, and Elsa was my favorite animated character until &lt;em&gt;Zootopia&lt;/em&gt; came about. This year, I went to see &lt;em&gt;Frozen II&lt;/em&gt;, it doesn’t have the same magical quality of the first one, of course. But something about it calms my wandering heart that has never been more lost and alone and scared of growing old. I can pursue the unknown even from within the safety of the castle, and someday, I will realize that &lt;strong&gt;I am the one I’ve been waiting for, all of my life&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2010s was fiery youth, incorruptible happiness, kaleidoscopic colors. It was dying in L.A., seeking directions and adapting to the lack thereof, and learning we are not what we thought we were. What was done, what was said — maybe it was a whole lot of baggage. But I also believe that if we find any way to a wild heart, one foot in front of another, and stay ‘til the A.M., god &lt;em&gt;will&lt;/em&gt; save our youngblood. Because, after all, being on top of the world, acting stupid for fun, living wild and free, that’s the way it’s supposed to be, no?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the meantime, I will play Long Live at exactly 23:58:57 so that I step into the new decade with “the start of an age.”&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Next decade, do the next right thing.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;也許世界就這樣&lt;br /&gt;
我也還在路上&lt;br /&gt;
新的十年，迎接星辰日出，再见孤独&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Personal" /><category term="Short" /><category term="Reflection" /><summary type="html">What did the 2010s mean to you? What do you remember? Late night procrastination, chilling watching television? Walking to Starbucks after school, walking to school from Starbucks? Crying when opening the college admissions portal, crying with the shower running only to be heard by your parents anyway? Was it a nightmare, a mad trip, a flavored kool-aid? Was it existential, or empty, or cold, sometimes lonely? Golden? like a Ferrari on Mulholland drive?</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Lover: The Evolution of Taylor Swift</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/lover" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Lover&amp;#58; The Evolution of Taylor Swift" /><published>2019-10-20T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2019-10-20T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/lover</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/lover">&lt;p&gt;We all remember the vengeful spirit of Taylor Swift. From claiming that “there’s nothing I do better than revenge” to “bandaids don’t fix bullet holes,” a certain part of her discography was dedicated to feuds and lost loves. Just two years ago, Taylor can be seen burning bridges and throwing shades, (in addition to being &lt;em&gt;presumably dead&lt;/em&gt;) in the music video for “Look What You Made Me Do.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If &lt;em&gt;reputation&lt;/em&gt; were a product of the venom and frustration that consumed her in the aftermaths of the Kim-Kanye controversy, then &lt;em&gt;Lover&lt;/em&gt; is the complete antithesis of that. With her newest release, Taylor delivers her most stylistically diverse and artistically complete body of work yet, featuring poignant introspection, playful maturity, and most importantly, a grand forgiveness, for both her enemies and herself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Regardless of the outcome of the drama, the existence of this album is proof of Taylor taking confident strides away from the days of bitter blame games. Realizing that contentions only feed into the bloodthirsty, clickbaity headline culture of today, Taylor also concludes that there are more important issues in life, such as the health of family members (“Soon You’ll Get Better”), political advocacy (“The Man”), and finding the one true love (“Lover”).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;a-past-in-the-past&quot;&gt;A Past in the Past&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 2006, Taylor Swift debuted as a country princess. She was heralded as “America’s Sweetheart,” that curly-haired girl next door who sang about love stories and fairytales. To be fair, it was fine for the 17-years-old Taylor to be petty, to sing about failed relationships and shitty boyfriends. But it did become problematic when people, including herself, seemed to forget that sweethearts grow up too, just like prom queens do not stay young forever and memories someday fade. When she gradually became complacent with an immaturity that resorted to triviality and revenge, it felt like a stagnancy in her creative direction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The halos also meant heightened expectation from fans and critics alike. During the release for &lt;em&gt;1989&lt;/em&gt;, both Swift and her music were recognized as perfection in the Pop universe. She had the flawless image, soaring sales numbers, all-star team of friends, and an award-winning album. Yet while she has reaped the benefits of media exposure, she also suffered — because public perception is an odd thing - the same people that crowned you can turn against you just as quickly. In today’s &lt;em&gt;stan-or-cancelled&lt;/em&gt; culture, the perfection demanded by the public can be exhausting. According to a recent &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.rollingstone.com/music/music-features/taylor-swift-rolling-stone-interview-880794/&quot;&gt;interview&lt;/a&gt; with The Rolling Stone, Taylor stated that “[people] decided in 2016 that absolutely everything about me was wrong. If I did something good, it was for the wrong reasons. If I did something brave, I didn’t do it correctly. If I stood up for myself, I was throwing a tantrum. And so I found myself in this endless mockery echo chamber.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/law-wang/moodblog/master/assets/images/lover2.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Cover&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;a-new-beginning&quot;&gt;A New Beginning&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In some bizarre way, however, her fall from grace also prompted the evolution of her artistry. Her once-teenager audience are now adults, and it seemed appropriate for her to grow out of the expectations and halos that once chained her. She did lose her perfect image, but in the death of her reputation, she became aware of the delicacy of herself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The Archer” is Taylor’s attempt to face that delicate part of her. The drum beats build a looming anxiety that lasts for the entirety of the track, creating an anticipation for climax, yet never reaching a cathartic moment. By depicting the uncertainty inherent to love, the song also reminds us that uncertainty is simply a fact of life, that things often do not have definitive ends, that somethings just become forgotten, trail off, and reach nowhere.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In that achingly sad moment of introspection, Taylor becomes aware of her shattered self as the veneers peeled away — she realizes that anyone can see right through her, just as she sings “I see right through me.” As the weariness finally washes over, the desperation for someone to stick around this time highlights precisely how there is no guarantee of it. After half a decade of jumping from romances, she understands that love stories are not as simple as “baby just say yes.” They may be complicated, messy, and inconclusive. Fairytales do not exist in real life, and if you want something, you have to fight for it — whether it be truth, vindication, or love.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;a-grand-forgiveness&quot;&gt;A Grand Forgiveness&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I guess the lesson &lt;em&gt;Lover&lt;/em&gt; brings is knowing ourselves. Understanding our own fragility makes us more accepting of others. Understanding our own defects makes us braver and more honest. “I Forgot That You Existed,” with playful and light presentation, contrasts greatly against the dark, gothic tracks from reputation. “It’s Nice To Have A Friend,” is the other side to “This Is Why We Can’t Have Nice Things.” Through a celebration of love and passion, she has learned to forgive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As dramas of the past dissipate, as the happy, the unhappy, the fortunate, and the unfortunate fade, Taylor Swift, in the spirit of moving on, bathes in “Daylight” and proclaims that “I wanna be defined by the things that I love. Not the things I hate. Not the things I’m afraid of, or the things that haunt me in the middle of the night.” She cannot remain America’s Sweetheart forever. Nobody can. Just like Rihanna’s modeling career and Gaga’s makeup line, there comes a time for Taylor to find her own voice. This time around, Taylor Swift announces that she will not be defined by resentment or snake emojis. Instead, she would like to be remembered by forgiveness, self-care, and maturity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everyone makes mistakes. We can all be seized by vengeance and rage. But more importantly, we also grow up, encounter ourselves, and find the things that matter more. Leaving the bad in the past — that is the victor’s attitude. Being defined by what you love — that is &lt;em&gt;Lover&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Music" /><category term="Taylor Swift" /><category term="Pop" /><category term="Featured" /><summary type="html">We all remember the vengeful spirit of Taylor Swift. From claiming that “there’s nothing I do better than revenge” to “bandaids don’t fix bullet holes,” a certain part of her discography was dedicated to feuds and lost loves. Just two years ago, Taylor can be seen burning bridges and throwing shades, (in addition to being presumably dead) in the music video for “Look What You Made Me Do.”</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Crazy Rich Asians: Socioeconomic Mismatch and The Farewell</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/crazy-rich-asians" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Crazy Rich Asians&amp;#58; Socioeconomic Mismatch and The Farewell" /><published>2019-08-03T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2019-08-03T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/crazy-rich</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/crazy-rich-asians">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Crazy Rich Asians&lt;/em&gt; is a movie that got many things right. The drama is great (albeit unrealistic at times), the performances by Constance Wu, Awkwafina, and Michelle Yeoh (soon debuting her own &lt;em&gt;Star Trek&lt;/em&gt; series!) are outstanding, the soundtrack — with heavy Asian-influenced curation (particularly the mandarin version of Yellow) — is touching. But it is also a movie that got a couple of key things wrong, and those significant flaws result in an identity crisis that diminishes the overall message.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://media1.s-nbcnews.com/i/newscms/2018_35/2543511/180824-crazy-rich-asians-al-1708_5a509f4d2866590468f39a0b86679796.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Cover&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;socioeconomic-mismatch&quot;&gt;Socioeconomic Mismatch&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I loved everything until Rachel boards the plane back to NYC. It’s perfect, and the mahjong scene brought me to tears. However, with the ending, the movie proceeds to dive off a 200-meter skyscraper. Here’s the thing, Rachel and Nick should NOT have ended up together. They don’t belong together — this is not my personal hot take, but a logical conclusion the film itself suggests.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the film, Astrid and Michael, a couple with great socioeconomic disparity, much like Rachel and Nick, end horribly with extramarital affairs and blame games. It serves as a premonition for all of us to consider socioeconomic forces as a potent disrupter in marriage, and sends a message to the audience that is in direct conflict with Rachel and Nick’s ending. Love can seem wonderful on paper, but marriage, as a union between two families, two upbringings, two ideologies, two cultures, is not the same. There are bound to be differences and obstacles, and what &lt;em&gt;Crazy Rich Asians&lt;/em&gt; seems to suggest, at least with Astrid and Michael, is that differences in wealth and background leads to an imbalance between the two parties, which eventually wears off the romance and passion, which eventually makes Michael feel inferior and sensitive and makes Astrid hide the jewels she loves that she bought with her own money. Under such premise of irreconcilable socioeconomic differences, how are we supposed to believe that Rachel and Nick will be any different? The story’s treatment of Astrid and Michael foreshadows what might be in store for Nick and Rachel, and if so, I’d rather have them miss each other than suffer an insufferable marriage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://api.time.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/08/crazy-rich-asians-gemma-chan.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Cover&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What we have to understand, is that although Rachel is modeled as the 21st century Cinderella, the plot should not be confined to the imagination of Cinderella. Rachel Chu is a self-made, modern woman and a professor at a world-renowned university — she represents the power of self-reliance. She deserves her own career, her own life, not living under someone else’s roof, subordinate to other people’s superiority. In this way, the film’s presentation of independence and individuality is confusing at best, and self-contradicting at worst.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When she goes back with Nick, underneath the glamor of the engagement party, there still exists the disdain, the supremacy deep in the bones of the elites who will never accept her and never see her as their equal. Nick’s insistence cannot suddenly change everyone’s mind, and Rachel will have to suffer the insincerity and hypocrisy of the elites forever. They might greet her, they might be nice to her, but both Rachel and they know that she will never be one of them. This is near-character assassination of Rachel. She’s presented as an earnest and pure soul, so why she would willingly subject herself to the eyerolls and being looked down on, for the rest of her life, I couldn’t possibly fathom.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;cultural-identity&quot;&gt;Cultural Identity&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aside from that, the all-Asian cast is commendable: it shows what multicultural representation in Hollywood and in the international media consumption market could look like. However, from a cultural perspective, the message of the film is less empowering. Essentially, the story presents a war of ideological values between the pan-Asian family-first culture and the Western desire for individual liberation. At its core, the film seems to be praising the Western way of life and derogatory towards the Eastern one, painting it as the antagonist. The set location, even, is Singapore, a place with historically significant colonial influence and westernized allegiance. The old money Crazy Rich Asians of the film still have to fortify a colonial facade with a good-enough-British-accent or the British-style-of-life. All of this seems not just blatantly inaccurate of the mainstream way of life, but also socially wrong.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://a468ba3fc2be117c5560-f9a6225d634730495a59b91d1543c5a4.ssl.cf5.rackcdn.com/_still/farewell-thumb-new2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Cover&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the contrary, &lt;em&gt;The Farewell&lt;/em&gt;, the 2019 title directed by Lulu Wang, portrays the family-first value of East Asian countries more accurately. The family wants the grandma to live her last days in peace, so everyone agrees to act in unison to protect her precious joy. There are no grand gestures, no luxurious setting, the shots are more commonplace, yet they strike with force more poignant than &lt;em&gt;Crazy Rich Asians&lt;/em&gt;, probably because &lt;em&gt;The Farewell&lt;/em&gt; is less about the idealized version of Asian life, and more about the elements of Asianness that affects a broader audience. The more unbiased presentation makes it more human.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I guess the takeaway is that Asians are cool and beautiful and smart, whether Constance Wu or Awkwafina, whether Rachel or Billi. There is nothing wrong with Asianness, there is nothing wrong with valuing one’s family — they are things we should embrace, and over the course of year, I’ve learned to embrace. There is no denying that &lt;em&gt;Crazy Rich Asians&lt;/em&gt; is a good movie, and that &lt;em&gt;The Farewell&lt;/em&gt; is a great movie, and both of them bring multicultural representation into the cinematic conversation. And I hope that with growing confidence of Asians everywhere, there will be more productions like these on the big screen.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Movie" /><summary type="html">Crazy Rich Asians is a movie that got many things right. The drama is great (albeit unrealistic at times), the performances by Constance Wu, Awkwafina, and Michelle Yeoh (soon debuting her own Star Trek series!) are outstanding, the soundtrack — with heavy Asian-influenced curation (particularly the mandarin version of Yellow) — is touching. But it is also a movie that got a couple of key things wrong, and those significant flaws result in an identity crisis that diminishes the overall message.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Eighteen</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/18" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Eighteen" /><published>2019-07-23T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2019-07-23T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/18</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/18">&lt;p&gt;18 would be a tie-dyed kaleidoscope of colors in my imagination: I would run around the neighborhood like I promise myself everyday (&lt;em&gt;and watch one less YouTube video&lt;/em&gt;). I would be driving around town ordering iced coffee at 1 A.M. (&lt;em&gt;because I would’ve gotten my DL before my permit expired&lt;/em&gt;). I would be getting ice cream at Venice, having spontaneous road trips, or visiting the Broad. I would actually have a senior quote (&lt;em&gt;thanks Troy High School&lt;/em&gt;), actually understand Chemistry, actually not care about school, and actually magically get a 5 on AP Spanish.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I would be fearless, free-spirited, and stupid-for-fun. I would’ve found my wild. Days would be drowning in screaming colors, nights would be shrouded in slow murmurs of the Pacific Ocean splashing on Huntington Beach.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, none of that happened. In retrospect, perhaps some of my hopes were unrealistic, strange, and unapologetically absurd. But then again, who said the me at 17 didn’t deserve to dream?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I guess reality is like water: it would never be as lively or rapid or possess the same relentless vigor as the waterfall of dreams. And like a river flows, time washes away the sharp edges, the deep yearnings, and the grand ambitions of dreams, until all its uniqueness and individuality are seemingly dulled by mediocrity and compromise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So now what? In light of the inevitable fall of dreams, end of youth, withering of all that’s bright and beautiful, are we to become senseless faceless inadmissible degenerates? Are we to be forever lost in the previous version of ourselves that is forever banished to the prison confining all supposedly immature wishes?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I still don’t own a record player. I still walk from school to Starbucks (&lt;em&gt;which apparently is like the most un-senior thing ever&lt;/em&gt;). I still sleep way too late and am way too serious about finding &lt;em&gt;the one&lt;/em&gt; (yogurt). My life is still not like &lt;em&gt;Love Simon&lt;/em&gt;, or &lt;em&gt;To All the Boys&lt;/em&gt;, or &lt;em&gt;The 100&lt;/em&gt;. I still feel so listless and empty after finishing every Chinese drama. I still haven’t gotten the letter in the mail that would pronounce me the Prince of Demark (&lt;em&gt;did you not know that?&lt;/em&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But none of that discounts the fact that I can find interesting things in the most banal tasks, and seek pleasure in the most desperate situations (&lt;em&gt;like my non-sensical conversation with Martha during the AP Spanish test, during which I’m sure neither of us understood each other!&lt;/em&gt;). I’ll find solace in empathy, thankfulness, understanding, and the belief that my terrible test grades in Stats are actually simply due to luck and not due to the pseudo-mathematics nature of statistics (&lt;em&gt;nor my inability to math in general&lt;/em&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s fair, I guess, to an extent. Not everything in life will be glittering mesmerizing breathtaking spectacles. Life is composed of little parentheses of losing and winning. We don’t get to win all the time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the end of the day, our world may be absurd, Meursault may be correct, Jake may never find the passion he desires, Estragon may remain forever waiting, there may never be an answer to the metaphysically posed yet historically diametrically answered question of the elusive meaning of existence, because, after all, once a week is quite enough to dine with one’s own relations, and the truth is rarely pure and never simple.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I’ll keep dreaming, keep counting stars like I’m 3, keep embracing the bigger wows, even though I might not be wiser now. ‘Cause I mean, who’ll be there to stop me?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And then, maybe my 18 will remain kaleidoscopically colored, forever.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Personal" /><category term="Reflection" /><summary type="html">18 would be a tie-dyed kaleidoscope of colors in my imagination: I would run around the neighborhood like I promise myself everyday (and watch one less YouTube video). I would be driving around town ordering iced coffee at 1 A.M. (because I would’ve gotten my DL before my permit expired). I would be getting ice cream at Venice, having spontaneous road trips, or visiting the Broad. I would actually have a senior quote (thanks Troy High School), actually understand Chemistry, actually not care about school, and actually magically get a 5 on AP Spanish.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">1989: It’s a Harry Styles Thing</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/1989" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="1989&amp;#58; It's a Harry Styles Thing" /><published>2019-06-30T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2019-06-30T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/1989</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/1989">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;1989&lt;/em&gt; was the album that took 2014 like storm. It’s known as a lot of things: the transformational work that marked the emergence of a pop queen from a country princess; the singer-songwriter’s comeback project to sweep all the award shows; the album that beat &lt;em&gt;To Pimp a Butterfly&lt;/em&gt; to Album of The Year at the 58th Grammy Awards; &lt;em&gt;you get the idea&lt;/em&gt;. But what intrigued me the most is how the album had &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Harry Styles&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; so blatantly written across its lyrical content and thematic presentation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Taylor Swift has never had a shortage of boy friends: whether it be Joe Jonas, or John Mayer, or Tom Hiddleston. Concurrently, it’s never been rare for Swift to write about them: whether it be We Are Never Ever Getting Back Together, or Dear John, and Getaway Car, respectively. But in &lt;em&gt;1989&lt;/em&gt;, Taylor documents her journey through love with a desolate determination, charming sweetness, and keen introspection. Taken together, the subject matter of every song— from New York City in Welcome to New York to London in Clean— chronicle the ups and downs in Swift and Styles’ relationship and narrate a most beautiful love story from beginning to end.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://hips.hearstapps.com/cosmouk.cdnds.net/14/37/nrm_1410270679-taylor-swift-harry-styles-hasnt-dated-rolling-stone-interview-cosmopolitan.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Cover&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-perfectly-styled-fantasy-story&quot;&gt;The Perfectly Styled Fantasy Story&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When they first started dating in the winter of 2012, they seemed like the perfect couple. One Direction was the international phenomenon, Taylor Swift was America’s Sweetheart: both talented, both paragons of their respective sexes, both with impressive fan bases. Both living in NYC— topic of the album’s first song. Some might call it the worst New York anthem ever, but I think it may very well be a celebration of the historic decision to move to NYC that allowed this love affair to develop, and in that sense, introduction to the bittersweet romance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The third track, Style has the most obvious connection to Harry. First, &lt;em&gt;the title&lt;/em&gt;. Second, the references, such as the “long hair, slicked back, white t-shirt” and the “James Dean daydream look in your eyes.” Third, Taylor said it herself in an interview:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“It’s basically one of those relationships that’s always a bit off. The two people are trying to forget each other. So, it’s like, “All right, I heard you went off with her,” and well, I’ve done that, too. My previous albums have also been sort of like, “I was right, you were wrong, you did this, it made me feel like this”—a righteous sense of right and wrong in a relationship. What happens when you grow up is you realize the rules in a relationship are very blurred and that it gets very complicated very quickly, and there’s not a case of who was right or who was wrong.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The relationship, according to Taylor, has never been a smooth ride. There’s been rumors of Harry Styles hooking up with other girls (which is semi-corroborated by herself). There’s been the thoughts of “Are we out of the woods yet? Are we in the clear yet?” in Out Of The Woods, the most vivid rendition of their love story on the album. We gain glimpses into their life together: the polaroid taken on their couch, the two paper airplane necklaces, the snowmobile accident during the skiing trip, the stitches and tears in the hospital room… All told with immense underlying emotion and, more importantly, bursting apprehension wondering whether the woods are just trees, where the next roadblock would be, how long this precious story would last, when it would end.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In I Wish You Would, the two have broken up, but the regret is eating both of their minds alive. Taylor has allegedly said that the song is about her ex who “bought a house literally one road adjacent to hers.” In Perfect, Harry mirrors Taylor’s lines: “windows down, you pass my street, the memories start” with “and if you like midnight driving with the windows down.” The story goes that every night, he would drive home, accidentally turn into her street, because he wanted to tell her how “he just wants to stop by her house and see her,” but he never did— because he thought she hated him now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, what he didn’t know is that she also stayed up watching his headlights pass by her windowpane, that “she’s still in love with him.” All the while he’s deciding whether to turn up at her house at 2 A.M., she’s hoping that he would. Turn right back around. Know that she’d never forget him. Know that she misses him too much to be mad at him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ultimately, that imperfect love is savored in Wildest Dream, in which Taylor wishes her lost love would see her in his dreams, and remember her the way he would remember him. No longer the vengeful spirit found in Better Than Revenge, Taylor’s first thoughts when entering a relationship are “when this ends, I hope it ends well. I hope you remember me well.” With imagery of the ocean and a maritime journey, This Love continues the reminiscence of the good times and the bad, as she relives moments of the love that left a permanent mark on her. As the sonic repetition of “this love” glide past our ears, we begin to feel those memories of love appearing and disappearing, but never leaving.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everything comes to a halt in Clean. Drafting dramatic metaphors of drought, the song symbolizes the absence of a relationship that once took up the artist’s entire world. For months all she could do was think about the good times. For months the memories haunted her. Until one day, all of a sudden, she realizes she’s been in London for two weeks and hasn’t thought about him. She’s fine, and she hopes he’s fine. In the pouring rain, the first thought that came to her mind was “I’m finally clean.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.vice.com/noisey/content-images/article/taylor-swift-1989-world-tour-review-essay/Screen-Shot-2015-07-13-at-11-40-25-AM.jpg?crop=1xw:0.9736752717391305xh;center,center&amp;amp;resize=1200:*&quot; alt=&quot;Cover&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-best-selling-coming-of-age-story&quot;&gt;The Best-Selling Coming-of-Age Story&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So that’s the story. Style outlines a timeless image. Out Of The Woods highlights a directionless anxiety. All You Had To Do Was Stay is the cheerful-tunes-shrouded melancholy of wanting it all back. How You Get The Girl is the instruction manual she wished he had followed to get her back. I Wish You Would conveys regret. This Love recounts the times that seem so beautiful in retrospect, and in Clean — it’s all gone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the end, they did not end up together. I never cared much about their relationship before, but after listening to the album knowing the Harry Styles undertones and hints, I can’t help but imagine what might have happened if the two did end up together. What if they held onto each other and cherished each other? In interviews, members of One Direction were always making fun of Harry about Taylor. Weren’t they Perfect for each other? Weren’t they meant for each other? Weren’t they supposed to never go out of Style and always be each other’s Wildest Dreams?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the audience, all we could ever do is listen to what artists have to say. We will never get the full picture. We will never know how beautiful the love was, how intense the fall out was, how acute the heartache was.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But what we do know is that &lt;em&gt;1989&lt;/em&gt; exemplifies the artist’s transformation from the girl sitting on bleachers, looking out the window to the boy next door, believing in fairy tales — to a woman understanding that not every romance will end like a fairy tale.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is an album about Harry Styles. It is an album to tell one story. Maybe it’s the love story of one fatalistic relationship. But more importantly, it’s a coming of age story of Taylor Swift. She realizes that not every relationship will have a knight in shining armor. She realizes fairy-tale endings are not a given, they are not how love is supposed to be:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“I think the way I used to approach relationships was very idealistic,” she says. “I used to go into them thinking, ‘Maybe this is the one — we’ll get married and have a family, this could be forever.’ Whereas now I go in thinking, ‘How long do we have on the clock — before something comes along and puts a wrench in it, or your publicist calls and says this isn’t a good idea?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://live.staticflickr.com/3584/3437428988_efb401a079_z.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Cover&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-real-love-story&quot;&gt;The Real Love Story&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Real love stories are not just the sassiness “she wears short skirts I wear T-shirts” or playfulness in “I can make a bad guy good for a weekend,” or the vengefulness in “she underestimated just who she was stealing from.” Love is more than seeing that single face in every crowd, and breakup is more than pointing fingers. It can be messy, difficult, painful. The lines are blurred. The right and wrong are mingled.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So &lt;em&gt;1989&lt;/em&gt; is more than a best-selling pop album, it tells the story of growth, of maturing, of self-discovery. Of a princess finding her prince charming but without a happily-ever-after. In her sophomore album Fearless, Taylor Swift used one chart-topping single to characterize an endearing love story. With &lt;em&gt;1989&lt;/em&gt;, it took her an entire album to do so. It’s a love story without “baby just say yes,” but it is more empowering, more precious, and more real, nonetheless.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The real love story is bittersweet, not nearly as dreamy as Love Story. But it’s more lively and contains much more strength. It comes with the realizations that love is not one-size-fits-all, that there might never be a happily-ever-after, and that resolutions might never exist. The anxiety might be overwhelming; the heartbreak might be unbearable. That’s what real love takes. That’s what make us believe that the imperfections in the fact that “I’m just a guy you’ll write breakup songs about” make the “red lips, little skirt, long hair, white t-shirt” style truly perfect.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Some information are excerpted from Tumblr.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Music" /><category term="Taylor Swift" /><category term="Pop" /><summary type="html">1989 was the album that took 2014 like storm. It’s known as a lot of things: the transformational work that marked the emergence of a pop queen from a country princess; the singer-songwriter’s comeback project to sweep all the award shows; the album that beat To Pimp a Butterfly to Album of The Year at the 58th Grammy Awards; you get the idea. But what intrigued me the most is how the album had Harry Styles so blatantly written across its lyrical content and thematic presentation.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Russian Doll: It’s Hard to Stay Alive</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/russian-doll" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Russian Doll&amp;#58; It's Hard to Stay Alive" /><published>2019-06-24T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2019-06-24T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/russian-doll</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/russian-doll">&lt;p&gt;You would think that after an entire school year of Nietzsche, Meursault, Godot, Kafka, Hemingway, and &lt;em&gt;Like Water for Chocolate&lt;/em&gt; in International Baccalaureate English would be enough absurdist discussion for a while, if not an entire lifetime. But &lt;em&gt;Russian Doll&lt;/em&gt;, the extremely odd, extremely beautiful, and extremely thought-provoking delight, proved to be just that piece of existentialism I never knew I needed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The sheer brilliance in the editing and cinematography is just the least of it: the message is what I find to be the most interesting. Particularly, the message that “it’s too easy to die that it’s hard to stay alive.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The series is deeply absurd, with the protagonist running into death in the most unexpected, dark-humor ways — at times, it’s nearly the real life version of Dumb Ways To Die. It’s also deeply existential, with a beautifully-crafted dialogue on which parts of the numerous ways to die actually convey the essence of life. It’s a story about two equally unfortunate people finding their own meaning of existence, and somehow that’s incredibly grand and moving.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;nadias-dilemma&quot;&gt;Nadia’s Dilemma&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Time passes by linearly throughout the show, but the main character, Nadia, is stuck on the night of her birthday party — the recycled moments of her waking up in front of the bathroom mirror is a diametric symbol of death and rebirth. Nadia and the other protagonist, Alan, theorized that the seemingly eternal time-loop is a punishment for their mistakes during their childhood. Nadia wanted to leave her mother, and attributed her mother’s death to her own fault, after which she decided to push other people away to avoid any possibility of genuine connection that might end up hurting both parties.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But through the eyes of Ruth, Nadia’s life-long friend and mentor, it was never Nadia’s fault. She was a tiny seed buried in darkness fighting her way to the light. She wanted to &lt;em&gt;live&lt;/em&gt;, and “it’s the most beautiful thing in the world.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As Ruth speaks arguably the most touching line of the series: “Do you still have that in you? I look at you now, chasing down death at every corner. Sweetheart, where is that gorgeous piece of you pushing to be a part of this world?” Nadia tears up, as would anyone who has felt the powerlessness of barely living, day to day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nadia is not a completely good person. Sometimes she’s not kind enough, or proactive enough, or friendly enough — she knows that about herself, so while she’s unforgiving of everything around her, that cynical attitude also extends to herself. She would appear tough, nonchalant, totally untouchable, absolutely inconsiderate, the consequences of which include a deep feeling of isolation and emptiness that can not be cured by the alcohol, or random sexual encounters, or an israeli-joint-highlighted birthday party.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Perhaps that’s her defense mechanism, of closing herself off from the world, thus eliminating the possibility of getting hurt and hurting other people. Or perhaps that’s who we all are — &lt;em&gt;incompletely good&lt;/em&gt; — as a result of our tendency to avoid pain and discomfort. But may I suggest to you that the experiences of bruising, the pain inherent to love, hate, and betrayal are the most real, human things, and that when we insulate ourselves from the world, we lose parts of what make us human in the first place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/law-wang/moodblog/master/assets/images/RD2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Cover&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;it-is-not-the-end&quot;&gt;It Is Not The End&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The ending is a beautiful moment. It has a quality that is as promising as &lt;em&gt;Groundhog Day&lt;/em&gt;, but not quite &lt;em&gt;Groundhog Day&lt;/em&gt;. The two protagonists reappear in front of their bathroom mirrors one last time and realize they are in different dimensions — the other person is back in cycle #1 and has no recollection of the death-defying adventures they shared together. Now, they have to look for the other person and convince them that all those hundreds of attempts at living and dying were actually real. As the screen splits in half, the audience witnesses a hopeful Alan assisting the turbulent Nadia, and a patient Nadia comforting the confused Alan. And as they walk through the winter New York streets, the two screens merge into one, with a renewed Nadia holding a torch, finally, again, pushing to be a part of this world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes, the mediocrity of daily chores and the pressures from expectations can make life feel like hell, like purgatory on earth. Sometimes, the anxiety of being alive strikes blows to us that seem impossible to handle. But as &lt;em&gt;Russian Doll&lt;/em&gt; reminds us, &lt;strong&gt;we are not alone in this world&lt;/strong&gt;. We still have each other, can find each other, and save each other. Just like in the ending when Nadia and Alan march, joining Horse’s parade of monsters, passing the shoulders of their alternative selves — &lt;em&gt;they have not given up on each other&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The world out there can be a vile one. A lonely one. A troubled one. One in which it’s hard to stay alive. But if we can all dig into our hearts, see ourselves for who we are, and learn to forgive and reconcile, maybe we can also let go of the cold, exoskeletal shells of protective covers; let go of the habit of keeping people at a distance; let go of the need to hide our insecurities and conceal our mistakes. In doing so, perhaps we might rediscover the fine world that is worth fighting for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;May this newfound hope and companionship in &lt;em&gt;Russian Doll&lt;/em&gt; mean that the past moments of “I just want to die” are not the end.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Television" /><category term="Netflix" /><category term="Featured" /><summary type="html">You would think that after an entire school year of Nietzsche, Meursault, Godot, Kafka, Hemingway, and Like Water for Chocolate in International Baccalaureate English would be enough absurdist discussion for a while, if not an entire lifetime. But Russian Doll, the extremely odd, extremely beautiful, and extremely thought-provoking delight, proved to be just that piece of existentialism I never knew I needed.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Commencement Address: Lessons I Learned</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/graduation" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Commencement Address&amp;#58; Lessons I Learned" /><published>2019-06-01T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2019-06-01T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/graduation</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/graduation">&lt;p&gt;Ladies and gentlemen, teachers, administrators, Class of 2019:  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Good evening. It is an absolute honor to be here. Six years ago, when I arrived in America, quite literally “fresh off the boat,” I never imagined I would be standing here. When I first stepped foot on Troy’s campus, I was entirely clueless about my future. Now, standing here at graduation, I know exactly the direction I’m going in life! Just kidding, I’m just as clueless as freshman year, but I do know that my experiences at Troy will serve as the foundation of whatever I decide to do in the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The past 4 years have been enlightening to say the least. I personally cannot count how many Spanish presentations I made (well at least now I know 15 is quince and not diecicinco), I learned that sometimes diamonds are produced from the pressures of procrastination, and who would’ve thought that the difficult times at Troy might actually bring people together!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I figured, since we’ve all seen the once clueless freshmen mature into aspiring models, journalists, entrepreneurs, and engineers, (oh and did I forget doctors?), since we’ve all witnessed how our eye bags grow exponentially on the daily during the college app season, and we’ve all heard about how we are “the worst case of senioritis” Mr. Rod has ever seen; so today, I would like to share some lessons I learned through the journey of high school with my fellow classmates, because it’s 2019 and sharing is caring.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First lesson is that you are what you love, and who loves you, but not who doesn’t love you. As a first generation immigrant, I used to be extremely self-conscious: of my appearance, of my slight accent (and my inability to English in general— to this day), and of anything that seemed mildly un-American. But through Troy, I learned that really, it doesn’t matter all that much. We all make mistakes and have our deficiencies, and that’s ok. A part of life is mastering the art of losing, losing the perfect image, losing that A+ in Fundamentals of Computer Science, and, most importantly, losing snapchat streaks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the contemporary poet and metaphysician Taylor Swift once said, we shouldn’t care so much if we feel misunderstood by a lot of people who don’t know us, as long as we feel understood by the people who do know us, who will show up for us, who see us as human beings. Sometimes I think it’s fearless to say goodbye to a situation that’s exhausting or toxic, and oftentimes, by leaving things behind and being yourself, you will find much broader horizons.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Second lesson is to build yourself up strong but humble. Surround yourself with positivity and support. Know that criticism doesn’t have to defeat you: it can strengthen you instead. We’re all different, and although it might not seem easy to get past the things we don’t always understand, remember that it is absolutely possible. And when you’re under attack, just think that the people who carry such negativity often have rather tragic lives themselves. So next time, pity them instead. Nobody is perfect, but humility always goes a long way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know, personally, that when Harvard University intimately tells us that they regret to inform us, or when Mr. Kim puts in that 0% on the acid-base titration Iodine Clock test, or when the all-nighter to cram the entire novel &lt;em&gt;Frankenstein&lt;/em&gt; is no longer sustainable even with multiple cups of coffee, it can seem like the end of the world. But I also know that rejections are natural to the human experience, and that in the long, long marathon of life, obstacles will show up every step of the way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But don’t ever let those obstacles sidetrack you, because it may be a fight to live an interesting life, but it’s a fight worth fighting for. Because if we are brave enough to chase after our ideals with unwavering determination, then there is a chance that we’ll succeed. Because I know that someday, when we get to where we’re going, the stories we write will be worth telling, and retelling, and listening to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So don’t become discouraged when the suffocating reality comes crashing down. Sometimes dreams are broken to make space for new ones. They represent a direction, but they’re not always the destination. Perhaps we don’t grow toward them, or for them. We grow to exceed them. Maybe we’re not quite ready for them today, but I know we’ll be ready &lt;em&gt;someday&lt;/em&gt;. If we don’t get there, we’ll get &lt;em&gt;somewhere&lt;/em&gt;. And I hope that the belief in someday, the dream of somewhere, will be our solace in midst of the ceaseless cluelessness of life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you for all the memories, Class of 2019, I am so glad to have had all of you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;divider&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/blog/graduation.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Cover&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Delivered May 31, 2019 at Troy High School’s Commencement Ceremony as valedictorian for the Class of 2019.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Personal" /><category term="Featured" /><category term="Reflection" /><summary type="html">Ladies and gentlemen, teachers, administrators, Class of 2019: Good evening. It is an absolute honor to be here. Six years ago, when I arrived in America, quite literally “fresh off the boat,” I never imagined I would be standing here. When I first stepped foot on Troy’s campus, I was entirely clueless about my future. Now, standing here at graduation, I know exactly the direction I’m going in life! Just kidding, I’m just as clueless as freshman year, but I do know that my experiences at Troy will serve as the foundation of whatever I decide to do in the future.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/graduation.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/graduation.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">To the Class of 2019</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/end-of-high-school" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="To the Class of 2019" /><published>2019-05-30T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2019-05-30T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/the-end</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/end-of-high-school">&lt;p&gt;Dear Classmates,  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
There won’t be another time when we get to dress up like nuns with our gowns, or jump up and down like insane, or throw our caps in the air and mess up the world - it’s what graduation means. A part of it inevitably means giving up some of the immaturity and innocence that characterized the teenage. &lt;em&gt;But may I suggest to you&lt;/em&gt; that we should not concede everything to the process of growing up. We can still be crazy, original, true to ourselves. The most distinguishing part of our individuality can never be lost or ceded. And I hope that someday, when we look back, we will know that we never strayed from our true path.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Remember that to be honest, what I liked, were the things I didn’t know. And that when it rains it pours, so stay thirsty like before. As Drake once said: “I guess you lose some and win some, long as the outcome’s income. I want it all, and then some.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
I want it all, and so should you.&lt;br /&gt;
Try to shine. Stay wild, C/O 2019.  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Yours,
Lawrence&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Personal" /><category term="Short" /><category term="Reflection" /><summary type="html">Dear Classmates, There won’t be another time when we get to dress up like nuns with our gowns, or jump up and down like insane, or throw our caps in the air and mess up the world - it’s what graduation means. A part of it inevitably means giving up some of the immaturity and innocence that characterized the teenage. But may I suggest to you that we should not concede everything to the process of growing up. We can still be crazy, original, true to ourselves. The most distinguishing part of our individuality can never be lost or ceded. And I hope that someday, when we look back, we will know that we never strayed from our true path. Remember that to be honest, what I liked, were the things I didn’t know. And that when it rains it pours, so stay thirsty like before. As Drake once said: “I guess you lose some and win some, long as the outcome’s income. I want it all, and then some. I want it all, and so should you. Try to shine. Stay wild, C/O 2019. Yours, Lawrence</summary></entry></feed>